Welcome to BC Central launch edition
2026 wave two and welcome to new video
in expense agent series.
In this video I will try to explain what
we improve in mileage handling.
So,
first I just explain what I already have
in
overview expense agent, but I just want
to repeat and then going straight
forward to demo.
>> [snorts]
>> So, earlier you could simple set up
mileage only one
amount for all different types of
mileages and we didn't have date range.
Now, if you have specific mileage
changes
from year to year or from month to
month, whatever situations, so you can
set set up what is starting and ending
date for your mileage allowance and then
you can set up immediately for the next
period, so you do not need to change in
the moment when you have new amount if
this is for example based on
authorities, so system will
automatically behave the last day of
previous period, system will use
previous allowance amount, in next
period system will use new allowance
amount. So, if you need this complexity,
you can go to mileage array setup and
you can set up a date range. If you
don't need, you can skip only one simple
model, so you are not supposed to use
this. On the other side, you can also
expand the setup different vehicle
types, so you can set up different
mileage for period and for different
vehicle types, so you can have for car,
for truck, for SUV, motorcycle, whatever
type of vehicle you are using, you can
set up without any problem and system
will use automatically. Okay, in vehicle
type situation you need to choose which
one you are using.
Okay, now let's go to the demo. I want
to explain where you can set up and how
to use this.
So, okay, where you need to set up? You
need to open expense agent setup
and you already have previous
setup here, standard rate of mileage.
So, if you put standard rate of mileage,
system will not look into do this new
complicated and more complex
mileage setup. You can use this simple
model if you do not have complex
business
needs. So, all good. This is what we
already had previously. But now, even
you have setup here,
if you configure your mileage rate
setup,
I have in my example here for 2026
rate for cars and for next year
different. So, it was 1.25, now 1.30
from next year and the same for trucks.
So, you can see I have different types
and different years.
For vehicle type, you have new table
where you can set up car, truck,
motorcycle, any type of
vehicle you are using and then you can
configure specific you can also use
currency code, but this is up to you.
You know, most of cases for mileage
companies are using local currency, so
you do not need to add local currency
here.
Okay, this is how you need to set up.
Now,
I am in expense agent and I want to
create new mileage.
Create mileage expense. So, I have new
one. Okay, from this address to
Microsoft, for example,
Microsoft LinkedIn.
Okay.
So, you can see what I have because I
have configured
vehicle vehicle types. If I didn't have,
system will not offer these vehicle
types, but as I have vehicle types, I
need to select which one and you will
see I didn't get calculated amount even
if I have 1.2 dollars
there in configuration because now I
have mileage
setup. So, in this case, I must choose
what I want to use. So, if this is car,
you can see calculate as 1.25. Why?
Because this is 2016
year. And if I choose truck, you will
see this is calculated 2.5 per miles.
Again,
this is amount for trucks and this is
based on in 2016. So, this is how system
it works. There is nothing special
there. So, we try to make this as more
automated as possible. So, only what you
need to do if you have different vehicle
types, you need to choose which one you
use. If you do not have different
vehicle types, you keep it simple.
System will look into your dates and
automatically populate your amount you
need to submit.
That's it about mileage. We try to keep
simple as simple as possible.
Thank you for watching this video.
>> [music]